Guide to the Black Caucus of Ithaca records, 1979-1981.
Black Caucus of Ithaca records, 1979-1981
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Black Caucus of Ithaca records, 1979-1981.
6572
Black Caucus of Ithaca.
0.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, newsclippings, typescripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Black Caucus of Ithaca records include materials concerning the civic organizations' work.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1979, the Black Caucus of Ithaca was founded for the purpose of dealing with education, affirmative action, economic development, political action and community relations as it related to issues and concerns of the Ithaca (N.Y.) black community.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Black Caucus of Ithaca records include materials concerning the organizations' work with education, affirmative action, economic development, political action and community relations as it related to issues and concerns of the Ithaca (N.Y.) black community. Of particular interest in the records of the Black Caucus of Ithaca are materials relating to the Sambo restaurant chain controversy that took place in 1979.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Black Caucus of Ithaca.; Black Caucus of Ithaca.; Sambo's Restaurant.
Subjects:
African Americans--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Political participation.; Boycotts.; Economic development--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Community involvement--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Affirmative action programs--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Minorities--Employment--New York (State)--Ithaca.
Places:
Ithaca (N.Y.)--Social Conditions.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- By-Laws and Purpose, Ca. 1979 -1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes and Agendas, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- News Articles, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Education Committee, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Civil Service, Ca. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Economic Development, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Affirmative Action Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Affirmative Action Responses, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sambo Restaurant Controversy Press Releases, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sambo History, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Sambo Corporation Responses, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- State Officials Responses, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Local Responses, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- National Responses, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Public Hearing, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- State Appeal, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Boycott Support, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Boycott Support, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Resolution of Support, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- News Articles, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Affirmative Action 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bernadette Powell Case (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Black Caucus Meetings and Events 1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Black Caucus Members Information (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Correspondence 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Ithaca School District 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ithaca College Incident 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Newspapers Clippings 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Sambo's Restaurant Controversy 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)